A Guide to the Papers of John A. Owen, Jr., 1951-1995
Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library, University of Virginia
Papers of John A. Owen, Jr. 1951-1995
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library, University of Virginia
MS-6
7.5 linear feet containing 15 boxes: 13 cm x 39.5 cm x 26.5 cm. Processed materials total 4,500 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Donation of Dr. John A. Owen, Jr., in 1996.
Biographical/Historical Information
John Atkinson Owen, Jr. was born on September 24, 1924 in South Boston, Virginia. He completed his B.S. degree from Hampden-Sydney College, Hamden-Sydney, Virginia and went on to obtain a M.D. from the University of Virginia in 1948. Owen's postdoctoral training was done in Cincinnati, Ohio, Charlottesville, Virginia, and Durham, North Carolina. From 1956-1958 he was an Assistant Professor of Medicine at the Medical College of Georgia. He then was Assistant Clinical Professor of Medicine at George Washington University School of Medicine from 1958-1960. In 1960 he was named an Assistant Professor of Medicine at the University of Virginia School of Medicine. In 1970 Owen became a full professor of Medicine at the same institution. Owen was married on November 29, 1952 to Wanda Earle Reamy. They had two children.
Scope and Content
The John A. Owen, Jr. collection consists of 15 boxes of archival material including letters, research notes, and documentation, and other items which reflect his professional activities from 1951-1995. The materials especially focus on diabetes, obesity, and endocrinology research; the relationship between pharmaceutical companies and physicians; federal regulations on prescription writing; and pharmacist-physician interaction. This collection is of special interest to scholars interested in the University of Virginia's clinical investigation during the 1960s-70s on diabetes and endocrinology; the relationship between pharmaceutical companies (and other organizations sponsoring basic research) and physicians; the effect of and response to federal legislation of the early 1970s which regulated prescription writing; the role of the pharmacist and their relationship to the physician; the interaction of the University of Virginia's department of medicine with the hospital's lab/pathology department; and the use of free samples from drug companies.
Arrangement
In accordance with the donor's provenance, the collection is organized into three parts. Chronological organization of what Dr. Owen considers his most important papers are located in boxes 1-6. Miscellaneous papers are in boxes 7-10. Alphabetic organization of extensive documentation of Dr. Owen's larger research projects and memorabilia from professional associations are in boxes 11-15.
Contents List
- 1955-1956 1955-1956, 5 TLS, 7 TL, 2 TD, 1 AD (Box-folder 001-001)
  RE: APPOINTMENT AT MEDICAL COLLEGE OF GEORGIA
- 1956-1958 1956-1958, 24 TLS, 21 TL (Box-folder 001-002)
- 1956-1958 1956-1958, 24 TLS, 21 TL (Box-folder 001-003)
  RE: COPIES OF ORIGINAL LETTERS FROM BOX 01 FOLDER 02
- 1957 1957, 9 TLS, 9 TL, 2 TD, 1 AD, 1 TMS (Box-folder 001-004)
- MT. ALTO JULY 1958-MAY 1959, 1 TD, 1 TDS, 5 TL, 43 TLS, 6 ALS, 4 TMS, 1 TELEGRAM (Box-folder 001-005)
- MT. ALTO JULY-DECEMBER 1958, 34 TL, 1 TM, 2 TLS, 2 TD (Box-folder 001-006)
- MT. ALTO JAN-JUNE 1959, 20 TL, 2 TLS, 2 TD (Box-folder 001-007)
- 1956-1957 1956-1957, 3 TD, 4 TL (Box-folder 001-008)
  RE: COPIES OF ORIGINIAL DOCUMENTS
- 1956-1957 1956-1957, 6 TL, 4 TLS, 7 TD (Box-folder 001-009)
  RE: MEDICAL COLLEGE OF GEORGIA
- 1959-1960 1959-1960, 18 TLS, 21 TL, 3 TD (Box-folder 001-010)
  RE: OWEN COMES TO UVA
- 1960 1960, 21 TLS, 26 TL, 3 ALS, 1 TD, 1 TM (Box-folder 001-011)
- 1961 1961, 1 PHOTO, 17 TLS, 23 TL, 2 ALS, 2 TM, 2 TD (Box-folder 001-012)
- JULY 1961-JUNE 1962 1961-1962, 1 TMS, 1 NEWSCLIP, 4 TD, 4 ALS, 20 TLS, 24 TL (Box-folder 001-013)
- JULY 1963-MARCH 1964 1963-1964, 4 TD, 1 AN, 3 ALS, 2 TM, 22 TLS, 35 TL (Box-folder 001-014)
- MARCH-JUNE 1964 1964, 12 TL, 13 TLS, 4 TD, 3 ALS, 1 TM (Box-folder 002-001)
- 1965 JULY-DECEMBER 1965, 1 AN, 3 ALS, 2 TM, 10 TD, 24 TLS, 21 TL (Box-folder 002-002)
- DECEMBER 1965-MARCH 1966 1965-1966, 6 ALS, 3 TM, 15 TLS, 18 TL, 1 TD (Box-folder 002-003)
- MARCH-JUNE 1966 1966, 4 TD, 2 TAL, 12 TLS, 20 TL (Box-folder 002-004)
- JULY 1966-JUNE 1967 1966-1967, 3 TL (Box-folder 002-005)
- OWEN--PHOTO CA. 1960'S, 1 PHOTO (Box-folder 002-006)
- JULY-OCTOBER 1970 1970, 1 ALS, 7 TD, 34 TLS, 27 TL (Box-folder 002-007)
- NOVEMBER 1970-FEBRUARY 1971 1970-1971, 4 ALS, 1 TD, 1 AD, 33 TL, 12 TLS (Box-folder 002-008)
- FEBRUARY 1971-JUNE 1971 1971, 22 TL, 9 TLS, 3 TD, 5 ALS (Box-folder 002-009)
- MAY-DECMBER 1967 1967, 4 TD, 1 TM, 2 ALS, 18 TLS, 35 TL (Box-folder 002-010)
- JANUARY-APRIL 1968 1968, 5 TD, 3 ALS, 15 TL, 33 TLS (Box-folder 002-011)
  RE: OWEN'S THOUGHTS ON EUTHANASIA
- APRIL-JUNE 1968 1968, 2 ALS, 2 TD, 8 TLS, 25 TL (Box-folder 002-012)
- JUNE-DECEMBER 1968 1968, 1 TM, 5 ALS, 20 TLS, 44 TL (Box-folder 003-001)
  RE: MISC. CORRESPONDENCE
- JANUARY-JUNE 1969 1969, 2 AN, 1 ANS, 3 ALS, 4 TD, 12 TLS, 41 TL (Box-folder 003-002)
- 1969 MAY-AUGUST 1969, 15 TLS, 30 TL, 1 TD, 2 ALS, 1 TM (Box-folder 003-003)
- 1969 OCTOBER-DECEMBER 1969, 49 TL, 21 TLS, 4 TD, 2 AD, 2 TLS, 1 TM (Box-folder 003-004)
- JANUARY-MARCH 1970 1970, 24 TL, 15 TMS, 2 TM, 1 ALS, 2 TD (Box-folder 003-005)
- APRIL-JUNE 1970 1970, 33 TL, 17 TLS, 1 AD, 5 TD, 1 ALS, 2 TM (Box-folder 003-006)
- JUNE-SEPTEMBER 1971 1971, 14 TLS, 33 TL, 7 TD, 2 ALS, 2 TM (Box-folder 003-007)
  RE: MISC. CORESPONDENCE
- OCTOBER-DECEMBER 1971 1971, 16 TLS, 40 TL, 3 TD, 1 TM (Box-folder 003-008)
- JANUARY-MARCH 1972 1972, 10 TLS, 17 TL, 2 TD, 1 TMS, 5 TM, A1 LS (Box-folder 003-009)
- APRIL-JUNE 1972 1972, 10 TLS, 26 TL, 1 TD, 4 TM, 1 TMS, 1 ALS (Box-folder 003-010)
- REPRINTS 1952-1953, 3 TD (Box-folder 004-001)
  RE: BUTTERWORTH, FROMMEYER, RISER, ENGEL, LEDERER, TREATMENT OF NEURITIS, ENDOCRINOLOGY, ROLE OF THE ADRENAL CORTEX IN INTERMEDIARY METABOLISM, ERTHROPHAGOCYTOSIS
- THE EDOCRINE CONTROL OF METABOLISM 1954, 1 TD (Box-folder 004-002)
  RE: FRANK ENGEL, DUKE UNIVERSITY, OWEN'S MENTOR
- REPRINTS 1955-60 (?), 12 TD (Box-folder 004-003)
- PHYSIOLOGY LABORATORY MANUAL 1956, 1 TD (Box-folder 004-004)
  RE: DUKE UNIVERSITY SCHOOL OF MEDICINE, ENDOCRINES
- HUMAN PROGRESS AND THE RACE PROBLEM 1956, 1 TD (Box-folder 004-005)
  RE: ADDRESS GIVEN AT DARTMOUTH COLLEGE BY W. C. GEORGE, ANTI-INTEGRATIONIST, RACISM
- CONFERENCE ON INSULIN ACTIVITY IN BLOOD AND TISSUE FLUIDS 1957, 1 TD WITH AN, 1 BOOKLET (Box-folder 004-006)
  RE: NIH
- 1958 1958, 22 TLS, 17 TL, 2 TDOC (Box-folder 004-007)
- SOUTHERN SOCIETY FOR CLINICAL RESEARCH ANNUAL MEETING 1958-1959, 2 TD (Box-folder 004-008)
  RE: ABSTRACTS
- CONFERENCE ON INSULIN AND THE ORAL HYPOGLYCEMIC AGENTS FEBRUARY 1959, 1 TD WITH AN (Box-folder 004-009)
  RE: INDIANA UNIVERSITY MEDICAL CENTER
- NUTRITION REVIEWS 1959, 1 BOOKLET (Box-folder 004-010)
  RE: ANALYSIS OF FATTY ACID MIXTURES BY GAS-LIQUID CHROMATOGRAPHY, ROCKEFELLER INSTITUTE
- PROGRAM PAPERS AND TALKS: DIABETES 1960 (?), 17 TD, 1 TL, 1 PROGRAM (Box-folder 004-011)
- ACETOHEXAMIDE, DRUG STUDY 1960-1961, T7 D, 21 TD WITH AN, 5 AD, 29 TLS, 17 TL, 1 TM (Box-folder 004-012)
- UNIVERSITY POLICY 1960-62, 3 TMS, 2 TD (Box-folder 004-013)
  RE: UVA PATENTS, INSURANCE
- REPRINTS 1960-63, 2 TDOC (Box-folder 004-014)
  RE: ART VS. SCIENCE OF MEDICINE, MR. JEFFERSON'S INFLUENCE ON AMERICAN MEDICAL EDUCATION
- ENDOCRINOLOGY AND METABOLISM MARCH 1961, 1 TD (Box-folder 004-015)
  RE: POSTGRADUATE COURSE IN UVA MEDICAL CENTER, EDOCRINOLOGY
- ALBEMARLE ANDIAMO AUTO CLUB [n.d.], 1 TD (Box-folder 004-016)
  RE: BYLAWS
- ALBEMARLE ANDIAMO AUTO CLUB 1961-62, 14 TL, 2 TLS, 1 MAGAZINE, 1 AL (Box-folder 004-017)
- MAJOR MED-X BLUE CROSS BLUE SHIELD 1962, 1 PAMPHLET (Box-folder 004-018)
  RE: INSURANCE
- VIRGINIA DIABETES ASSOCIATION, INC. 1962, 1 TD, 1 TLS (Box-folder 004-019)
  RE: DIABETES, MEMBERS LIST
- BIOCHEMISTRY SEMINARS 1960-1964, 18 TD (Box-folder 004-020)
  RE: BIOCHEMISTRY
- BIOCHEMISTRY SEMINARS 1964-1966, 19 TM, 4 AD, 2 TD (Box-folder 004-021)
- GRANT INFORMATION 1960-1963, 8 TD (Box-folder 004-022)
- GRANTS: HOSPITAL ANNOUNCEMENTS, ETC. 1961-62 (?), 7 TD, 1 TLS (Box-folder 004-023)
- VINTAGE CAR STORE 1961-62, 3 TL, 1 TD (LEGAL DOC), 1 CAR DOC (Box-folder 004-024)
- METABOLIC ABNORMALITIES OF ADIPOSE TISSUE, DIABETES 1962, 2 TD, 3 TLS, 3 TL, 1 AN (Box-folder 005-001)
  RE: DIABETES, METABOLISM
- MISC. CORRESPONDENCE 1962-1970, 11 TL, 1 ALS, 1 TLS, 1 TD (Box-folder 005-002)
- PHARMACEUTICAL MANUFACTURERS ASSOCIATION:TALK CLINICAL PHARMACOLOGY 1964, 18 TLS, 11 TL, 9 TD (Box-folder 005-003)
- MCNEIL DRUG--742 STUDY 1964-1965, 10 TL, 12 TLS, 6 TD (Box-folder 005-004)
- PHARMACY AND THE PHYSICIAN 1964-67 (?), 7 TD, 21 TLS, 2 TL, 2 ALS (Box-folder 005-005)
  RE: NEWSLETTER, PHARMACY AND THE PHYSICIAN
- METABOLIC MOUSE LAB RENOVATION 1965, 3 TD, 1 TM, 1 AMS, 1 TL (Box-folder 005-006)
- PAPERS AND ABSTRACTS: HUMAN PHARMACOLOGY OF ANTI-THYROID DRUGS 1965, 3 TD, 1 TL (Box-folder 005-007)
  RE: CLINICAL PHARMACOLOGY, ANTI-THYROID DRUGS
- 1966 A.F. JOHNSON, 2 TL, 1 AD (Box-folder 005-008)
  RE: PATIENT, DIABETES, CONFIDENTIAL
- AMERICAN COLLEGE OF CLINICAL PHARMACOLOGY AND CHEMOTHERAPY 1965-1966, 2 TLS (Box-folder 005-009)
- AMERICAN COLLEGE OF CLINICAL PHARMACOLOGY AND CHEMOTHERAPY 1965-1966, 1 TL, 5 TLS, 10 TD, 1 PAMPHLET (Box-folder 005-010)
  RE: PHARMACOLOGY AND CHEMOTHERAP
- AMERICAN SOCIETY OF CLINICAL PHARMACOLOGY AND CHEMOTHERAPY 1966-1969, 1 TL, 4 TLS, 9 TD, 1 PAMPHLET (Box-folder 005-011)
  RE: ACCPC DIRECTION, SUGGESTIONS BY OWEN
- AMERICAN SOCIETY FOR CLINICAL PHARMACOLOGY AND THERAPEUTICS 1966-1971, 2 PAMPHLET, 4 TLS, 8 TD (Box-folder 005-012)
- JOHN ANDERSON 1966, 1 TLS, 1 ALS, 1 TD (Box-folder 005-013)
  RE: INHIBITORY EFFECT OF CAFFINE ON THE IN VITRO UPTAKE OF GLUCOSE BY RAT EPIDIDYMAL ADIPOSE TISSUE
- STATE LICENSE 1966, 1 TD (Box-folder 005-014)
  RE: APPLICATION FOR MEDICAL LICENSE
- RESTRICTED ACCESS 1966-1970, 4 TLS, 3 TL, 2 AD, 1 AN, 5 TD (Box-folder 005-015)
  RE: HIPPA
- STUDENT ELECTIVE PROGRAMS 1964-1965, 6 TM WITH AN, 3 TL, 5 TLS, 5 TD, 3 AN (Box-folder 005-016)
- JOHN G HADDAD, JR. 1966, 6 TL, 4 ALS, 1 T/AD, 1 PHOTO (Box-folder 005-017)
  RE: CONFIDENTIAL, ENDOCRINOLOGY TRAINING PROGRAM
- NATIONAL DISEASE AND THERAPEUTIC INDEX 1966-1967, 2 TD (Box-folder 005-018)
  RE: MEASLES--THE CURRENT DECLINE, LEADING DIAGNOSES AND REASONS FOR PATIENT VISITS
- PHARMACOLOGY SEARCH COMMITTEE 1966-1967, 1 TD (FROM BINDER) (Box-folder 005-019)
  RE: PHARMACOLOGY SEARCH COMMITTEE UVA
- NAVY 1966-1973, 5 TDOC (BOOKLETS) (Box-folder 005-020)
  RE: NAVY, OWEN WAS NAVY REPRESENTATIVE, COUNSELED STUDENTS ABOUT NAVY SCHOLARSHIP, INTERN, RESIDENCY PROGRAMS
- VIRGINIA SOCIETY OF INTERNAL MEDICINE 1967, 5 TD, 1 TMS (Box-folder 005-021)
  RE: INTERNAL MEDICINE VIRGINIA
- CHARLOTTESVILLE, VIRGINIA 1967, 1 ALS, 2 TL, 1 TLS, 1 TD, 1 MAP (Box-folder 005-022)
- PENTEX, INC. 1967, 2 AD, 1 TLS, 1 TL (Box-folder 006-001)
  RE: DRUG STUDY
- PENTEX, INC. 1967, 1 CATALOGUE (Box-folder 006-002)
  RE: DRUG
- ARNEL PRODUCTS COMPANY 1967, 1 CATALOGUE (Box-folder 006-003)
  RE: LABORATORY PRODUCTS
- PHARMACOLOGY SEARCH COMMITTEE 1967, 1 TL, 9 TLS, 19 TD, 11 TM (Box-folder 006-004)
  RE: PHARMACOLOGY SEARCH COMMITTEE
- CAMBRIDGE NUCLEAR CORPORATION 1967-1968, 3 TLS, 1 TL (Box-folder 006-005)
- ALBEMARLE COUNTY MEDICAL SOCIETY: PHARMACY COMMITTEE 1967-1968, 15 TD, 4 TLS, 2 TL, 1 TMS, 1 TMS, 6 TM (Box-folder 006-006)
- ORIENTATION SU-19165 CIBA PHARMACEUTICAL CO. 1968, 1 TD (Box-folder 006-007)
- PROBLEMS AND PROGRESS IN NEW DRUGS 1968, 2 TD, 1 ALS, 16 TL, 7 TLS (Box-folder 006-008)
- ANNUAL LICENSE FEE 1968-1971, 6 TD, 1 TMS (Box-folder 006-009)
  RE: MEDICAL LICENSE
- UVA MEDICAL ALUMNI ASSOCIATION 1974, 2 TD, 1 TL, 1 AN (Box-folder 006-010)
  RE: CLASS REP (1948)
- PHYSICIAN-PHARMACIST VOLUNTARY PROGRAM TO IMPROVE PRESCRIPTION PRACTICES 1969, 3 TD, 3 TL, 1 TMS, 1 TDS, 3 TLS (Box-folder 006-011)
- DIAZOXIDE 1969-1970, 1 TMS (Box-folder 006-012)
- DR. WITT: DE JARNETTE STUDY OCT-NOV 1970, 2 TL, 2 TLS (Box-folder 006-013)
- CALCITONIN STUDY 1970-1972, 1 AN, 7 TL, 9 TLS, 2 ALS, 12 TD, 2 AD (Box-folder 006-014)
- ANNUAL REPORTS: DEPT. INTERNAL MEDICINE DIV. CLINICAL PHARMACOLOGY 1970-1971, 9 TD, 1 TM (Box-folder 006-015)
- OUT PATIENT DEPARTMENT: DRUG POLICY 1970-71, 15 TLS, 3 TMS, 6 TD, 2 AD, 1 TL, 1 ANS, 4 TM (Box-folder 006-016)
- DIAZOXIDE STUDY 1970-71, 3 TLS, 1 TL, 1 TD (Box-folder 006-017)
- DRUG INTERACTIONS 1971, 4 TLS, 8 TD, 3 TL (Box-folder 006-018)
  RE: A PH A STUDY, DRUG INTERACTIONS
- DRUG INTERACTIONS 1971, 7 TD (Box-folder 006-019)
- DRUG INTERACTIONS 1972, 8 TD, 4 TL, 5 TLS, 2 AN (Box-folder 006-020)
- UNITED STATES PHARMACOPEIA: CLINICAL PHARMACY CONCEPT 1971, 1 TM, 4 TD, 4 TL, 2 TMS, 8 TLS (Box-folder 007-001)
- UNITED STATES PHARMACOPEIA: CLINICAL PHARMACY CONCEPT 1971, 21 TLS, 3 TMS, 2 TD, 1 TL (Box-folder 007-002)
- BNDD 1971, 2 TL, 5 TD, 1 TD WITH AN, 5 TLS, 4 AN, 4 TMS, 11 TM (Box-folder 007-003)
  RE: NEW LAW FOR WRITING PRESCRIPTIONS, RAMIFICATIONS AND RESPONSE FROM PHYSICIANS
- FOOD AND DRUG ADMINISTRATION: COMMUNICATION WITH PHYSICIANS 1971-1972, 4 TL, 1 TLS, 2 TD, 1 AN, 1 AD (Box-folder 007-004)
  RE: FOOD AND DRUG, PHYSICIANS AND PHYSICIANS' NEEDS
- FOOD AND DRUG ADMINISTRATION: SURVEY OF THE DRUG INFORMATION NEEDS JAN 1972, 1 TD (Box-folder 007-005)
  RE: DIRECTED TO PRACTICING PHYSICIANS, FOOD AND DRUG ADMIN.
- FOOD AND DRUG ADMINISTRATION: QUESTIONNAIRE--PHYSICIANS & DRUG INFO 1972-1973, 1 AD, 1 AN, 1 ANS, 3 TD, 5 TL, 5 TLS (Box-folder 007-006)
- TOLBUTAMIDE TEST 1971-1973, 9 TD, 5 TL, 5 TLS, 3 AD, 1 ALS, 1 AN, 1 PHOTO (Box-folder 007-007)
  TOLBUTAMIDE TEST, DRUG STUDY
- PHYSICIAL DIAGNOSIS COURSE 1970-1974, 5 TL, 2 TM, 1 TD, 3 AD (Box-folder 007-008)
  RE: STUDENT EVALUATIONS, FINAL EXAM, CONFIDENTIAL
- SELF-STUDY UVA DEPARTMENT OF INTERNAL MEDICINE 1972-1973, 1 TMS, 1 TLS, 2 TD, 2 MANUAL (Box-folder 007-009)
  RE: SOUTHERN ASSOC. OF COLLEGES AND SCHOOLS OWEN
- MEDICAL SOCIETY OF VIRGINIA FEB-APRIL 1972, 26 TLS, 26 TD (Box-folder 007-010)
  RE: RESEARCH ABSTRACTS FOR PROGRAM
- 1972 MEDICAL SOCIETY OF VIRGINIA, 5 TL, 3 TM, 10 TLS, 3 TD, 2 TNS, 1 PROGRAM (Box-folder 007-011)
  RE: PROGRAM COMMITTEE
- CENTRAL LAB ADVISORY BOARD OCT-NOV 1973, 4 TL, 14 TLS, 8 TM, 21 TD, 2 ANS, 2 AN (Box-folder 007-012)
  RE: PROBLEMS BETWEEN MEDICINE DEPARTMENT AND LAB--DEPT OF PATHOLOGY
- EPHEMERAL CLERKSHIP COMMITTEE OCT-NOV 1973, 3 TD, 2 TMS, 1 TLS (Box-folder 007-013)
  RE: STUDENT ROTATIONS, GOALS OF MEDICINE CLERKSHIP
- ENODOCRINE SOCIETY [N.D.], 1 TD (Box-folder 007-014)
  RE: NOMINATION FORM
- ENDOCRINOLOGY STUDY SECTION [N.D.], 1 TD (Box-folder 007-015)
  RE: BIOCHEMISTRY STAFF PUBLICATIONS
- A.H. ROBINS COMPANY, INC. 1965 (?), 8 TD, 1 TLS (Box-folder 008-001)
  RE: STUDY PROTOCOL, DRUG STUDY-FENFLURAMINE
- A H ROBINS CO., INC. FENFLURAMINE STUDY JULY 1965, 1 TD (Box-folder 008-002)
  RE: INVESTIGATIONAL BROCHURE, FENFLURAMINE STUDY, DRUG STUDY
- A H ROBINS CO., INC. AHR-0840C AUGUST 1965, 1 TD (Box-folder 008-003)
  RE: INVESTIGATIONAL BROCHURE, DRUG STUDY
- A H ROBINS CO., AHR-0840C 1966-1967, 4 TD, 1 TLS (Box-folder 008-004)
- A H ROBINS 1967, 2 TLS, 1 TD, 1 TL (Box-folder 008-005)
- FENFLURAMINE STUDY 1962-66, 4 TD, 3 TLS, 4 TL (Box-folder 008-006)
  RE: ANEREXIGENIC DRUGS STUDY PROTOCOL, REPRINTS, CORRESPONDENCE
- FENFLURAMINE, PRE-SATE 1964-1966, 2 TL, 2 TLS, 3 TD (Box-folder 008-007)
  RE: FENLFURAMINE DRUG STUDY, CHEMICAL ENTITY FOR OBESITY
- FENFLURAMINE-METHAMPHETAMINE STUDY 1966-67, 13 TD WITH AN (Box-folder 008-008)
  RE: FENFLURAMINE DRUG STUDY, GRANT #4879 CLINICAL DATE FORMS
- FENFLURAMINE-METHAMPHETAMINE STUDY 1966-1967, 7 TD, 1 AD (Box-folder 008-009)
  RE: FENFLURAMINE DRUG STUDY, GRANT #4879 STUDY PROTOCOL
- FENFLURAMINE-METHAMPHETAMINE STUDY 1966-68, 11 TLS, 16 TL, 1 TM, 1 TD (Box-folder 008-010)
  RE: FENFLURAMINE DRUG STUDY, GRANT #4879 CORRESPONDENCE
- STUDY PROTOCOL 1968, 1 TD (Box-folder 008-011)
  RE: FENFLURAMINE EXTENSION
- STUDY DATA [N.D.], 1 AD, 1 TD (Box-folder 008-012)
  RE: DRUG STUDY DATA
- FENFLURAMINE 1968-1969, 13 TD, 1 TMA, 18 TLS, 13 TL, 1 BROCHURE (Box-folder 008-013)
  RE: FENFLURAMINE DRUG STUDY, TABLETS VS. EXTENTAB
- FENFLURAMINE STUDY: DR. J.A. OWEN, JR. [N.D.], 1 NOTEBOOK (Box-folder 008-014)
- GEIGY STUDY 1969, 1 TDS, 3 TL, 12 TLS, 1 TD/ADS (Box-folder 008-015)
- PROTOCOL--BLANK STUDY DOCUMENTS [N.D.], 3 TD (Box-folder 008-016)
- GLUCOLA STUDY AND CORRESPONDENCE 1964-65, 1 AN, 5 TD, 7 TLS, 7 TL, 1 PAMPHLET (Box-folder 009-001)
- GLUCOLA-DDD 1968, 8 TD, 2 TDS, 20 TLS, 19 TL, 1 TM, 1 AD (Box-folder 009-002)
- GLUCOSE TOLERANCE TESTING 1967-68, 5 TD, 2 TL, 11 AD, 1 TDS, 8 GRAPHS, 1 TM (Box-folder 009-003)
  RE: GLUCOSE TOLERANCE TESTING, STUDY
- BIBLIOGRAPHY ON GLUCAGON [N.D.], 1 TD (Box-folder 009-004)
  RE: PIERO FOA AND ANNA D'AMICO
- MEDICAL STATISTICS NOTES 1959-1965, 3 TD, 2 TM, 33 TLS, 29 TL (Box-folder 009-005)
  RE: MEDICAL STATISTICS NOTES
- MEDICAL STATISTICS NOTES 1959, 10 TD (Box-folder 009-006)
  RE: NOTES FROM A LABORATORY OF MEDICAL STATISTICS
- MEDICAL STATISTICS NOTES 1960-1962, 11 TD (Box-folder 009-007)
- MEDICAL STATISTICS NOTES 1963, 20 D (Box-folder 009-008)
- MEDICAL STATISTICS NOTES 1963, 14 TD (Box-folder 009-009)
- MEDICAL STATISTICS NOTES 1964, 15 TD (Box-folder 009-010)
- MEDICAL STATISTICS NOTES 1964, 12 TD (Box-folder 010-001)
- MEDICAL STATISTICS NOTES 1964, 17 TD (Box-folder 010-002)
  RE: NOTES FROM A LABORATORY OF MEDICAL STATISTICS, NOTES #80-93, INCLUDES LIST OF TITLES AND INDEX
- MEDICAL STATISTICS NOTES 1965, 16 TD (Box-folder 010-003)
  NOTES FROM A LABORATORY OF MEDICAL STATISTICS, NOTES #94-110
- MEDICAL STATISTICS NOTES 1965, 21 TD (Box-folder 010-004)
  RE: NOTES FROM A LABORATORY OF MEDICAL STATISTICS, NOTES #128-145
- MEDICAL STATISTICS NOTES 1965, 17 TD (Box-folder 010-005)
  NOTES FROM A LABORATORY OF MEDICAL STATISTICS, NOTES #111-127
- NIH GRANT A-4036 SERUM INSULIN 1961-1963, 5 TD, 1 ALS, 1 TN, 3 TL, 3 TLS, 1 TM, 1 PAMPLET (Box-folder 010-006)
  RE: NIH GRANT SERUM INSULIN
- NIH GRANT A-4036 SERUM INSULIN 1962-1963, 9 TL, 9 TLS, 2 TMS, 5 TM, 16 TD (Box-folder 010-007)
- NIH TRAINING GRANT CLINICAL PHARMACOLOGY 1962-1966, 2 TL, 2 TLS, 11 TD, 4 AD, 2 TM, 1 TMS (Box-folder 010-008)
- NIH GRANT: DIABETES TRAINING 1964, 3 TM, 2 TD (Box-folder 010-009)
- 1958 ORINASE, 1 TD (Box-folder 011-001)
- ORINASE 1958, 6 TD (Box-folder 011-002)
- UPJOHN COMPANY: A NEW ORALLY ACTIVE ANTIDIABETIC AGENT 1961, 1 TLS, 1 TD (Box-folder 011-003)
  LAB INFOR, UPJOHN DRUG STUDY
- UPJOHN STUDY 1968-74, 1 AD, 5 N, 2 ANS, 26 TL, 29 TLS, 26 TD (Box-folder 011-004)
- UPJOHN CLINICAL STUDIES 1968-1969, 3 TLS, 2 TD (Box-folder 011-005)
  RE: U-26452 DRUG STUDIES
- UPJOHN STUDY FEB 1969, 1 TD (Box-folder 011-006)
  RE: CLINICAL BROCHURE
- UPJOHN STUDY, U-26452 1970 (?), 6 TD, 1 TLS, 1 AD (Box-folder 011-007)
- RESEARCH NOTES [N.D.], 1 TD, 19 AN, 1 BROCHURE (Box-folder 011-008)
- PROGRAM ADVANCE PROGRAMME OF THE FIFTH CONGRESS OF THE INTERNATIONAL DIABETES FEDERATION 1964, 1 PROGRAM (Box-folder 011-009)
  RE: INTERNATIONAL DIABETES FEDERATION PROGRAM
- PROGRAMS: AMERICAN DIABETES ASSOCIATION 1958-1960, 3 PROGRAM (Box-folder 011-010)
  RE: AMERICAN DIABETES ASSOCIATION, ANNUAL MEETING PROGRAMS, 18TH-20TH MEETINGS
- AMERICAN DIABETES ASSOCIATION 1961, 1 TDOC (BOOKLET) (Box-folder 011-011)
  RE: AMERICAN DIABETES ASSOCIATION MEMBERSHIP DIRECTORY
- 1961-63 AMERICAN DIABETES ASSOCIATION, 3 PROGRAMS (Box-folder 011-012)
  RE: AMERICAN DIABETES ASSOCIATION, ANNUAL MEETING PROGRAMS, 21ST-23RD MEETINGS
- AMERICAN COLLEGE OF CLINICAL PHARMACOLOGY AND CHEMOTHERAPY 1965-66, 1 TDOC (BOOKLET) (Box-folder 011-013)
  RE: CLINICAL PHARMACOLOGY AND CHEMOTHERAPY DIRECTORY
- 1951-1955 AMERICAN SOCIETY FOR CLINICAL INVESTIGATION, 4 PROGRAMS (Box-folder 012-001)
  RE: CLINICAL INVESTIGATION ANNUAL MEETING PROGRAMS, 43RD-47TH MEETINGS
- AMERICAN SOCIETY FOR CLINICAL INVESTIGATION 1956-1959, 4 PROGRAMS (Box-folder 012-002)
  RE: CLINICAL INVESTIGATION ANNUAL MEETING PROGRAMS, 48TH-51ST MEETINGS
- AMERICAN SOCIETY FOR CLINICAL INVESTIGATION 1960-64, 5 PROGRAMS (Box-folder 012-003)
  RE: CLINICAL INVESTIGATION ANNUAL MEETING PROGRAMS 52ND-56TH MEETINGS
- ASSOCIATION FOR THE STUDY OF INTERNAL SECRETIONS 1951, 1 PROGRAMS (Box-folder 012-004)
  RE: INTERNAL SECRETIONS 33RD MEETING PROGRAM
- THE ENDOCRINE SOCIETY 1955-1960, 7 PROGRAMS (Box-folder 012-005)
  RE: ENDOCRINE SOCIETY ANNUAL MEETING PROGRAMS, 37TH-42ND MEETINGS
- THE ENDOCRINE SOCIETY 1961-63, 3 PROGRAMS (Box-folder 012-006)
  RE: ENDOCRINE SOCIETY ANNUAL MEETING PROGRAMS, 43RD-45TH MEETINGS
- THE ENDOCRINE SOCIETY 1964-66, 3 PROGRAMS (Box-folder 012-007)
  RE: ENDOCRINE SOCIETY ANNUAL MEETING PROGRAMS, 46-48TH MEETINGS
- 1972 CORRESPONDENCE 1972, 7 TLS, 13 TL, 2 ALS, 3 TMS, 4 TM, 1 TD (Box-folder 013-001)
  RE: MISC.
- 1972-1973 1972-1973 CORRESPONDENCE, 15 TLS, 24 TL, 8 TD, 2 TMS, 4 TM, 2 ALS (Box-folder 013-002)
- 1974 CORRESPONDENCE 1974, 14 TD, 6 TM, 4 ALS, 28 TLS, 50 TL (Box-folder 013-003)
- 1975 CORRESPONDENCE 1975, 56 TL, 25 TLS, 6 TD, 6 ALS, 3 TM, 1 TMS (Box-folder 013-004)
  RE: MISC
- 1976 CORRESPONDENCE 1976, 21 TL, 12 TLS, 2 TM, 1 TMS, 1 AMS, 2 TD, 1 AD (Box-folder 013-005)
- 1977 CORRESPONDENCE 1977, 16 TLS, 31 TL, 5 ALS, 9 TD, 6 TM, 2 AN (Box-folder 013-006)
- 1978 CORRESPONDENCE 1978, 44 TL, 27 TLS, 1 TMS, 1 TM, 7 TD, 2 ALS (Box-folder 013-007)
- 1979 CORRESPONDENCE 1979, 2 TM, 9 TL, 8 TLS, 1 TD (Box-folder 013-008)
- 1980 CORRESPONDENCE 1980, 25 TL, 10 TLS, 5 TMS, 3 TD, 1 ALS (Box-folder 013-009)
- 1981 CORRESPONDENCE 1981, 21 TL, 6 TLS, 2 TM, 1 TMS, 2 TD, 5 ALS (Box-folder 014-001)
- 1982 CORRESPONDENCE 1982, 22 TL, 8 TLS, 1 AD, 3 ALS, 2 TM, 3 TD, 1 NEWSCLIPS (Box-folder 014-002)
- 1983 CORRESPONDENCE 1983, 11 TL, 4 TLS, 1 TM, 2 ALS, 1 TD (Box-folder 014-003)
- 1984 CORRESPONDENCE 1984, 29 TL, 26 TLS, 2 ALS, 12 TD (Box-folder 014-004)
- 1985 CORRESPONDENCE 1985, 16 TLS, 20 TL, 3 ALS, 6 TD (Box-folder 014-005)
- 1986 CORRESPONDENCE 1986, 14 TL, 10 TLS, 5 TD, 1 ALS, 3 TM, 1 TMS (Box-folder 014-006)
- 1987 CORRESPONDENCE 1987, 8 TLS, 1 TD, 1 TM (Box-folder 014-007)
- 1987 CORRESPONDENCE 1987, 26 TLS, 7 TL, 5 TD, 1 ALS, 5 TMS (Box-folder 014-008)
- 1988 CORRESPONDENCE 1988, 19 TLS, 1 TL, 1 TD, 2 TMS, 1 AD (Box-folder 014-009)
- 1988 CORRESPONDENCE 1988, 28 TLS, 3 ALS, 4 TD, 1 TMS (Box-folder 014-010)
- 1989 CORRESPONDENCE 1989, 66 TLS, 3 TL, 8 TD, 2 TM, 7 TMS, 1 NEWSCLIP (Box-folder 014-011)
- 1990-1991 CORRESPONDENCE 1990-1991, 56 TLS, 3 ALS, 1 NEWLETTER, 5 TMS, 1 TD (Box-folder 015-001)
- 1991 CORRESPONDENCE 1991, 10 TLS, 2 ALS, 3 TMS (Box-folder 015-002)
- 1992 CORRESPONDENCE 1992, 32 TLS, 1 TL, 4 ALS, 2 TD, 3 TMS (Box-folder 015-003)
- 1993 CORRESPONDENCE 1993, 15 TLS, 1 TMS, 1 ALS, 3 TD (Box-folder 015-004)
- 1994 CORRESPONDENCE 1994, 14 TLS, 2 ALS, 1 TD, 1 CARTOON (Box-folder 015-005)
- 1995 CORRESPONDENCE 1995, 21 TLS, 2 TMS, 7 TD, 4 TL (Box-folder 015-006)
- TO JOHN OWEN FROM ELIZABETH BROWN MULHOLLAND [GAMBLE] [N.D.], 1 ALS (Box-folder 015-007)
  RE: WIDOW OF DR. HENRY MULLHOLLAND EXPRESSES INTEREST IN DIABETES ADVISORY COMMITTEE
- DR. LOBSAND DOLMA - TIBETAN MEDICINE 1974-1975, 42 ALS, 1 PHOTO, 24 TLS, 4 TL, 7 NEWSCLIPS, 1 TM, 1 TD (Box-folder 015-007)
  RE: DR. DOLMA'S VISIT TO UVA & CORRESPONDANCE RESULTING FROM THAT VISIT & SUBSEQUENT MEDIA COVERAL